Equal Justice USA; Records apap358
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Equal Justice USA Records
1975-2021
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap358
14.8 cubic ft.
This collection documents Equal Justice USA's efforts to abolish capital punishment and reform the criminal justice system nationwide. It focuses in particular on the organization's campaign for a nationwide moratorium against the death penalty in 2000, as well as records leading up to and resulting from this campaign.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Equal Justice USA Executive Director Shari Silberstein in 2008 and 2016. Silberstein packed up additional records in 2021 and they were then donated by the organization in 2022.
Historical Note
Equal Justice USA is a national organization that seeks to create a fair, effective criminal justice system. Its campaign to end capital punishment, particularly its nationwide campaign for a moratorium during the year 2000, is the group's largest and longest-standing program. Equal Justice USA also frequently partnered with other organizations, both national and local, on both sides of the political aisle, including the Quixote Center. These partnerships aim to dismantle oppressive systems and protect historically underserved citizens.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials discussing Equal Justice USA's efforts to abolish capital punishment and reform the U.S. criminal justice system. Included are subject files, clippings, mailings to Equal Justice USA supporters, other correspondence, organizational projects and programs, state files, death penalty moratorium resolutions, legislative resources, annual reports, newsletters, some case files, and audio/video resources.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Separated Materials
The archivist transferred several monographs: 10.10 is World Day. Abolish the Death Penalty. It's a Better World Without It. 10 October 2012 World Day Against the Death Penalty, report by the World Coalition Against the Death Penalty; Death Sentences: 34 Classic Short Stories About the Death Penalty by Chekhov, Tolstoy, Poe, Dunbar, Balzac, Twain, Kafka, Dickens and More Great Writers edited by Susan Ives; Irreversible Error: Recommended Reforms for Preventing and Correcting Errors in the Administration of Capital Punishment, a Report of the Constitution Project's Death Penalty Committee; Mandatory Justice: The Death Penalty Revisited by The Constitution Project; Moratorium 2000: Abolition of the Death Penalty at the 54th UN Commission on Human Rights edited by Hands Off Cain; No Justice: No Victory. The Death Penalty in Texas by Susan Lee Campbell Solar; Shall Suffer Death by A.J. Bannister; Teaching Abolition: 10 October 2009 World Day Against the Death Penalty, report by the World Coalition Against the Death Penalty; Towards Abolition: The Law and Politics of the Death Penalty, 1998 Report edited by Hands Off Cain; Truth Be Told: Life Lessons From Death Row, Correspondence of Agnes and Richard Nields; Twisted Truth: A True Account of the Struggle for Justice of a Death Row Inmate by Wendy Schmid-Eastwood; Waiting to Die: A Death Row Missioner Researches Death by Virginia Walden Hogue to the book division of Special Collections. They will be catalogued and included in the University Library Catalog.
Capital punishment -- United States; Files by subject; Clippings; Correspondence; Annual reports; Resolutions (administrative records); Death Penalty; Death row inmates.; Criminal Justice and Prisons; Human rights workers.; Equal Justice USA
- 20 Steps to Winning a Moratorium Bill, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 70x7: The Forgiveness Equation, 2008 (Dvd 1)
- ABA Call for a Moratorium on Executions, Undated (Video-tape 1)
- ABA Death Penalty Resolution, 1996-1997; 1999-2000; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ABA Executing Injustice, Undated (Cd 1)
- ABA Moratorium Progress, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Abolition, 2001 (Cd 1)
- ACLC, 1990; 1999; 2003-2004; 2009; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Action Packets, 2002; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Address to the Prisoners in the Cook County Jail, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Addressing Capital Punishment through Statutory Reform, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Administrative (1 of 1), 1987; 1998; 2000; 2004; 2013 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Administrative (2 of 2), 1987; 1998; 2000; 2004; 2013 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- After Innocence, Undated (Video-tape 2)
- Agendas Training/Strategy, 2004-2005; 2007-2008; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Alabama, 1998-2006; 2008-2009; 2011; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alabama Death Penalty Assessment Report, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alaska, 1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Already Executed, 2000-2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- American Bar Association, 1989; 1999-2000; 2002; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- American Bar Association, Death Penalty, Moratorium Call to Action, 1997; 2000-2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- American Bar Association Journal, 1999-2000; 2000; 2003; 2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- American Trends Service Committee, 1998; 2000; 2003; 2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Amnesty International (1 of 2), 1988-1989; 1998-1999; 2001; 2003-2006; 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Amnesty International (2 of 2), 1988-1990; 1998-2000; 2002-2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Amnesty International Poster, Undated (Map-tube 1)
- Anchorage Mail, 2008; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Annual Reports, 1997; 2001-2012 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Appeals, 1996; 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- April Direct Mail, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Arizona, 1990; 1999-2000; 2002; 2010; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Arizona Death Penalty Assessment Report, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Arkansas, 1998-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- At the Death House Door, Undated (Cd 3)
- Back on Death Row, 1999 (Video-tape 3)
- Baltimore Ban Ad, 2001; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bear Lincoln, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Benetton Booklet, 2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Billboard Campaign Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bill Copies, 1992; 2002; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bloodworth, lnc., 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Bold Dreamer Invite, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Booklets (small), 2000; 2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Botched Executions, 1997; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Breach of Trust, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bruderhof Movement, 1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- By-Laws, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- California (1 of 2), 1998-2001; 2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- California (2 of 2), 1998-2002; 2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- California People of Faith PowerPoint, Undated (Cd 4)
- Calls From Home, 2003 (Cd 5)
- Capital Punishment on the 25th Anniversary of Furman vs. Georgia, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Capitol News Briefing, 2011 (Cd 6)
- Capitol News Briefing, 2012 (Cd 7)
- "Catholic", 2005-2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Catholic Mill, 2005; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Catholic Mobilizing Network, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Celebration Event, 2008; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Citizens United for Alternatives to the Death Penalty, 1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- City Council Resolutions, 1998-2002 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- City Councils, 2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Class, 2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Coleman, Roger Keith, 1991; 2001; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Colorado, 1998-2000; 2002-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Colorado Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Columbia Human Rights Law Review, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Community of Sant Egidio, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Conference on Wrongful Executions, 1998; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Conference Programs, 2009-2010; 2014; Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Connecticut, 1998-2001; 2004; 2006-2007; 2012; Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Connecticut Post Card/Magnet, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty, 2013-2014; 2017; Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Constitution Project, 2000-2001; 2010; Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Correspondence to EJUSA, 1989; 1995; 1997; 2000; 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Court of Appeals Filings-Taylor Case, 2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Court Rulings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Court Rulings, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Court Rulings, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Court Rulings, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Crime, 1991; 1997; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- CT Murder Victims Families Ask Legislative to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2011 (Cd 8)
- CUADP, 1998-2000; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Deadline, 2004 (Dvd 2)
- Deadline, 2004 (Video-tape 4)
- Dead Man Walking, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Dead Man Walking Plan Project, 2000; 2003-2004; 2010; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, 1983; 1990; 1995; 2000-2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- The Death Penalty and Mental Illness, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- The Death Penalty Curriculum, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Death Penalty Information Center (1 of 2), 1990; 1992-2001; 2004-2007; 2009; 2011 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Death Penalty Information Center (2 of 2), 1990; 1992-2001; 2004-2007; 2009; 2011 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Death Penalty Moratorium Implementation Project, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Death Penalty: New Progress Towards Abolition, 2010 (Cd 9)
- Death Without Justice, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- December Annual Report, 2009; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- December Annual Report, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- December Mailing, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Declaration of Life, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Delaware, 1999-2001; 2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Department of Justice Race Study, 2000-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Deterrence, 1998; 2000-2001; 2006; Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Direct Mail, 1998; Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- District of Colombia, 1991-1992; 1997; Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Dudley Sharp, 2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- EJ USA Internal Planning, 2002-2003; 2006; Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- EJ USA Press Quotes, 2011; 2014; Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
- EJ USA YouTube, 2011 (Cd 10)
- El Paso County Commissioners Court, 2002 (Video-tape 5)
- Equal Justice USA Banner/Pins, Undated (Artifact-box 1)
- Erskine Johnson, Wilbert Lee, Alton Wayne, Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Evaluating Fairness Accuracy in State Penalty Systems, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Ex-Inmate Re-Entry, 1999; 2002; Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Eyewitness I.D, 2001; Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Faith in Action, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Fairness, 1982; 1990-1992; 1995; 1998; Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Fall Direct Mail, 2001; Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Fall LCWR, 1998; Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Federal, 1991-1995; Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Federal Bill Copies, 1999-2001; Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Fielding McLehee vs Equal Justice, 2007; Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- File/Folder #11 (Edith A. Monsees), 1992; 1994-1995; 2001; 2005; Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Florida (1 of 2), 1998-2008; Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Florida (2 of 2), 1998-2008; Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Florida Death Penalty Assessment Report, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Friends Committee to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1996-1997; Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- GA Conference, Undated (Cd 11)
- GAO/ General Accounting Office (1 of 2), 1990-1993; 1996 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- GAO/ General Accounting Office (2 of 2), 1990-1994; 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- General Info (1 of 3), 2000-2001; 2003-2007; 2009-2011; 2013-2014; Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
- General Info (2 of 3), 2000-2015; Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- General Info (3 of 3), 2000-2016; Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Genetics and Violence, 1992; Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Geographic Arbitarity, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Georgia, 1998-2003; 2005-2006; Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Georgia Death Penalty Assessment Report, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Getting to Death, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Giarratano, Joseph, 1991; Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Graham, Gary, 1994; 1999-2000; Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Grassroots Investigation Project, 2000; 2003; Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Grey Jr., Anthony, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Grassroots Investigation Project, 2006; Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Hands Off Cain Conference, 1999; Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Hawaii, 2000-2009; Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Heir to an Execution, 2003 (Video-tape 6)
- Historical Materials, Undated (Cd 12)
- Holiday Cards, 2003; Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Holiday Postcard, 2001; Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Honrar La Vida, Undated (Dvd 3)
- Illinois (1 of 2), 1997-2002; 2006-2009; Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Illinois (2 of 2), 1997-2002; 2006-2009; Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Illinois Declare Moratorium, 1999-2000; 2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Illinois Repeal Party, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Indiana (1 of 2), 1998-2002; 2005; 2010; Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Indiana (2 of 2), 1998-2003; 2005; 2010; Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Indiana Catholic Conference, Undated (Dvd 4)
- Indiana Death Penalty Assessment Report, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Indignant Counsel, 1988; 1996; 2000; Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Innocence, 2002-2005; Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Innocence Conference, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Intellectual Disability, 2001; Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Interchange Death Penalty Moratorium, Undated (Cd 13)
- Internal Messaging, 1998; 2002; Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
- International Endorses, 1998-2002; 2004; Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
- International Opinion, 1999; 2001; 2004-2007; Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Interview With an Executioner, 2003 (Cd 14)
- Iona, 1997-2001; 2004-2005; Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Iowa Law Review, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- It's A Miracle: American Justice, Undated (Cd 15)
- Jeffrey Deskowic: Wrongful Convictions, Undated (Cd 16)
- "Jewish", 2001; Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
- John Taylor Brief from Richard Brown (1 of 2), 2007 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- John Taylor Brief from Richard Brown (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Johnson, Erskine, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Journey of Hope Awards Ceremony, 2005 (Cd 17)
- Judiciary/Judges, 1996; 1998-2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- The Justice Project, 2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Juveniles, 1990-1993; 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Kansas, 1999-2006; Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Kay Kay and the Rays: Texas Justice, 2001 (Cd 18)
- Kentucky, 1999-2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Labor, 2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Lake Forest Panel Discussion, 2012 April 11 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Law Enforcement for a Moratorium, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
- LCWR Mailing, 1997; Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
- LCWR Mailing, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Legislative Toolkit, 2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Legislative Tracking, 2000-2002; Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Lent Message to NCR, 1999; Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Lenten Group Appeal, 1999; Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Lethal Injection, 2002; 2006; Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Letter (Silberstein), Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Letterhead, Logo Specs, 1999; Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Let the Evidence Be Heard, Undated (Cd 19)
- Liebman Study (1 of 2), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Liebman Study (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Life Without Parole, 2000; 2007; Undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Lifers who Kill Again, 2005; Undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
- List of Other Countries' Death Penalty Positions, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Logan/Ivey Postcard, Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Louisiana, 1990; 1999-2021; Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Mailing 19, 1997; Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Mailing 21, 1997; Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Mailing 22, 1997; Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Mailing 24, 1998; Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Mailing 25, 1998; Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Mailing 27, 1998; Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Mailing 28/28D, 1999; Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Mailing 29/29D, 1999; Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Mailing 30/30D, 1999; Undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Mailing 31/31D, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Mailing 33, 2000; Undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Mailing 34, 2000; Undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Mailing 35B/H, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Mailing 35H, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Mailing 36, 2000; Undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Mailing 37, 2000; Undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Mailing 38, 2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Mailing 39, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Mailing 40, 2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Mailing 41, 2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Mailing 42, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Mailing 45, 2002; Undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Mailing 46 B/H, Undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Mailing 48, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Mailing 49, 2003; Undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Mailing 49, 2004; Undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Mailing 50, 2003; Undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Mailing 51, 2003; Undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Mailing 54, 2002; Undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Mailing 55, 2004; Undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Mailing 56, 2004; Undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Mailing 57, 2004; Undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Mailing 58, 2005; Undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Mailing 59, 2005; Undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Mailing 60, 2005; Undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Mailing 61 Annual Report, 2006; Undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Mailing 63, 2006; Undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Mailing 64 Annual Report, 2007; Undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
- Mailing 65, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 64)
- Mailing 66, 2007; Undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
- Mailing 67, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Mailing 68, 2007; Undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
- Mailing 70, 2008; Undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
- Mailing 71, 2008; Undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
- Mailing 72, 2008; Undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
- Mailing 73, 2008; Undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Mailing 74, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 72)
- Mailing 77, 2009-2010; Undated (Box 6, Folder 73)
- Mailing 78, 2010; Undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
- Mailing 79, 2010; Undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
- Mailing 80, 2011; Undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
- Mailing 81, 2011; Undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
- Mailing 83, 2002; Undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
- Mailing 84, 2011; Undated (Box 6, Folder 79)
- Mailing 85, 2011; Undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
- Mailing 86, Undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
- Mailing 89, 2012; Undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
- Mailing 90, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Mailing 93, 2014; Undated (Box 6, Folder 84)
- Mailing 97, Undated (Box 6, Folder 85)
- Mailing 98, 2015; Undated (Box 6, Folder 86)
- Mailing 99, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 87)
- Mailing 100, 2015; Undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
- Mailing 102, 2016; Undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
- Mailing, Cameron Todd Willingham, 2009; Undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
- Mailing, Dead Man Walking, 2000; Undated (Box 6, Folder 91)
- Mailing, Presidential Election Season, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 92)
- Maine, 1998-2001; Undated (Box 6, Folder 93)
- Maryland, 1997-2003; 2006-2007; 2009; Undated (Box 6, Folder 94)
- Maryland Commission Capital Punishment, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Maryland Committee for Responsible Corrections Policy, 1991-1993; Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Maryland Hunt Execution, 1993; 1996-1997; Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Maryland Mailings (and other mailings), 2005-2006 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Maryland Moratorium Campaign (1 of 2), 1998-2001; Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Maryland Moratorium Campaign (2 of 2), 1998-2001; Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Maryland Press, 2002-2005; Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Maryland Repeal Campaign (1 of 2), 2006-2012 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Maryland Repeal Campaign (2 of 2), 2006-2012 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Maryland Study Commission (1 of 2), 2008; Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Maryland Study Commission (2 of 2), 2008; Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Massachusetts, 1995; 1998-2001; Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Materials Listing, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
- May Newsletter, 2011; Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
- McVeigh, Timothy, 1997; 2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- MD Action Alert, ca. 2004 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- MD Postcard, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Medical, 1988; 1990; 1994; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Mental Illness, 2001; 2005-2006; Undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Michigan, 1990; 1998-2002; Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Minnesota, 1998-2001; Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Misc. Materials, 1999-2000; Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous Workshops, 2008; Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Mississippi, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Mississippi Death Row Hunger Strike, 1986; 1988; 1991; Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Missouri (1 of 2), 1997-2010; Undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Missouri (2 of 2), 1997-2010; Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Model Resolution Mailings, Undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Momentum [Liebman Study Draft] (Away from Death Penalty), Undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Montana, 1998-1999; 2000-2005; Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Moral/Ethical (non-religious), 2006; Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Moratorium, 1999; 2001; 2006; Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Moratorium Debates/Votes/Public Hearings, Undated (Video-tape 7)
- Moratorium Mail, 1997-1998; 2000; Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Moratorium Now Mailer, Reports, 2001-2003; 2006-2008; Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Moratorium Now Organizing Packet Materials, 2001; Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Moratorium Now Resolution Campaign, 1998-2001; 2003; Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Moratorium On Executions, 2002 (Video-tape 8)
- Moratorium Working Group, 1998-1999; Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Moving Beyond Sides, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Memia Letter, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Murder Rates, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Murder Victims Families for Human Rights, 2005; 2008-2011; Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation, 1999; 2001; 2004-2006; Undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
- NACDL State Legislative Network Conference, 2008 (Cd 20)
- Nancy Grace Show, 2005 (Cd 21)
- National Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers, 1999; Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
- National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (1 of 2), 2004; 2006; 2009; Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
- National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (2 of 2), 2004; 2006; 2009; Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
- National Commission, 2005-2007 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- National Commission on Capital Punishment, 1995-1996; Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
- National Groups, 1998-2002; 2004; 2006; Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
- National Lawyers Guild, 2000-2002; Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
- National Weekend of Faith In Action on the Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- National Weekend of Faith In Action on the Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- National Weekend of Faith In Action on the Death Penalty, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- National Weekend of Faith In Action on the Death Penalty, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- NCADP Annual Conference, 2004 (Cd 22)
- NCADP Annual Conference, 2006 (Cd 23)
- NCADP Annual Conference, 2008 (Cd 24)
- NC Racial Justice Act, Undated (Cd 25)
- Nebraska, 1997-1999; 2001; 2003; 2008-2009; Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Nevada, 1999-2002; Undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Nevada Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- New Hampshire, 1997-2000; 2012 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- New Jersey (1 of 3), 1998-2002; 2004-2007; 2009 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- New Jersey (2 of 3), 1998-2002; 2004-2007; 2009 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- New Jersey (3 of 3), 1998-2002; 2004-2007; 2009 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- New Jersey Death Penalty, 2004; 2006; Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- New Jersey Press, 2003; 2006-2007; Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
- New Mexico, 1998-2006; Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
- New York (1 of 2), 1998-2003; 2007; Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
- New York (2 of 2), 1998-2003; 2007; Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- New York Communications and Legislature, 2004-2005; 2007; Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
- New York Communications from the Legislature, 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- New York Info and Research, 1985-1986; 1999-2004; Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
- New York Post Abolition, 2010; 2013; Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
- New York Pre-Moratorium, 1998-2002; Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
- New York Press, 2004-2005; Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)